# Clissman J. Camacho

Phone: +56 9 44183405

Email: <u>clissmancamacho@gmail.com</u>
Website: <u>clissmancamacho.com</u>

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/clissmancamacho/

Software Engineer with +6 years of experience, specialized in the creation and maintenance of web and mobile applications. I use languages like JavaScript, PHP, Python, Ruby; and their respective frameworks: NodeJs, Nest, React, Angular, Vue, Laravel, Flask, FastAPI, Django, Ruby on Rails, etc. I have 2 years of experience leading teams of 3 to 6 members, carrying out strategic actions for the development of projects. I have the capacity for critical thinking, decision making, problem solving and self-taught attitude. I am interested in applying my skills in different industries, developing innovative solutions.

## Areas of Knowledge

- Using JavaScript since 2017, React since 2019 and VueJS since 2022.
- Using different (JS/Node, PHP/Lumen/Laravel, JAVA/Spring, PYTHON/Flask/FastAPI/Django, RUBY/Rails) Backend languages since 2017.
- Good knowledge of new technologies in general.
- Experience leading a team of 5 people on a cell in government projects.
- Learning about new technologies in Infrastructure and Application Deploy.
- Likes to teach and learn every day.

### **Professional Experience**

#### **Buk – Senior Software Engineer (april 2023 – Present)**

Development of software for human resources management.

- Development of services in Ruby on Rails.
- Use of PostgreSQL as data persistence layer.
- Unit tests and TDD.
- Planning with PMs and team for refinement and estimation of tasks.
- Work with the QA member to solve doubts about new implementations.
- Meetings with other senior developers defining improvement and refactoring plans for reduce technical debt.
- Review of pull/merge request.
- Scrum Methodology, using management tools such as Jira and Notion.
- Github as code repository.

#### Kuantaz - Tech Lead (february 2023 - april 2023)

Software Development Leader for Government projects.

- Construction of project from scratch.
- Development of microservices in Python (Flask).
- Implementation of ACL to guarantee the security in the access of the microservices.
- Frontend development with Vue 3 (Nuxt 3).
- Event handling with Apache Kafka.
- Unit tests.
- CI/CD
- Planning with PMs for refinement and estimation of tasks
- Use of PostgreSQL as data persistence layer.

- Construction of infrastructure with AWS CDK.
- Deployment of applications in AWS.
- Scrum Methodology, using management tools such as Jira and Notion.
- Github as code repository.

#### Ewok Ingenería S.A – Senior Full Stack Developer and Team Leader (october 2019 – january 2023)

Full Stack development and team management in different projects of the Chilean government, focused on the optimization and availability of high-demand services.

- Development of a platform that shows in a personalized way the benefits that the Chilean government can provide to a person according to their profile. (https://www.reddeproteccion.cl/)
- Lead developer of a Platform created to reduce the impact of the covid-19 emergency. In it, Chilean citizens could request, consult and claim the Emergency Family Income (https://www.ingresodeemergencia.cl/).
- Use of PostgreSQL and MySQL as data persistence layers.
- Use of Redis as cache.
- Event handling with AWS SQS.
- Frontend development with ReactJS.
- ETL implementation with Pentaho.
- Migrate the entire backend of a Project from Lumen to Laravel in 1 week.
- Web scraping with Python to obtain updated information from portals of other ministries.
- Code review and approval.
- CI/CD.
- As a leader, he guided Scrum ceremonies and went 1 on 1 with team members.
- Talks every 2 weeks presenting the team with new technologies and opportunities for improvement.

#### Freelance Software Developer (january 2019 – september 2019)

Analysis, design and development of different web systems and mobile applications:

- Development of mobile app with Ionic/Angular2 and backend in nodejs/express
- Development of tire management system with Laravel.
- Development of customizations and modules for Django-CMS with Python.
- Automation of daily tasks with Python scripts for various clients.
- Development of new features and correction of bugs in Java software.
- Implementation of components in VueJS on a static site.
- Deployment of applications using GCP (Compute Engine).
- Gitlab as code repository.

#### Agrauco – Fullstack Developer (september2017 – January 2019)

- Development of REST APIs with NodeJs.
- Use of MongoDB as a data persistence layer.
- Use of Angular as a framework for the frontend.
- Gitlab as code repository.
- Deployment of applications using GCP (Compute Engine)

# **Education**

### Universidad Central de Venezuela – Barchelor of Computer Science

Approved studies up to the 6th semester of the Degree in Computer Science.

# Languages

English (B1), Spanish (native)

# **Hobbies**

- Soccer fan and amateur player.
- Fan of the stock and cryptocurrency market.
- I play guitar in my free time.